Guide to the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites MSS.496
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Khumalo, Andile, April 2014-February 2015; Khumalo, A. W.; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Andile Khumalo (b. 1978) is a South African composer and lecturer in music theory at the University of Witwatersrand. Some of Khumalo's notable works include Tracing Hollow Traces (2014), Human Cries (2014), Schaufe[r]nster II (2014), Bells Die Out (2013), Shades of Words (2011), and Ossia (2010).
  The website featured a biography, a list of compositions, a photo gallery, a list of links, and contact information. As of 2023, the website has been taken down.
- Kim, K. Marie, September 2016-November 2024; cuid5889; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of kmariekim.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website does not exist. It contained examples of her compositions in the form of embedded audio and video files and a biography of the artist. It also had information about her album releases and performances.
  K. Marie Kim Papers (MSS 504)
  Parts of the live site involving SoundCloud, Bandcamp, and YouTube were not captured due to technological constraints.
  K. Marie Kim is a Korean-Canadian composer, audio engineer, and clinical audiologist based in Vancouver, British Columbia. Kim's music incorporates multiple instruments and electronic elements. She is also a performer on the cello and piano. Kim used to be based in Brooklyn, New York, where she performed as the keyboardist for the singer-songwriter Mitski. She was an audio engineer for multiple organizations including the YouTube Space in New York and venues such as Terminal 5, Webster Hall, Brooklyn Steel, and the Music Hall of Williamsburg.
- Kimura, Mari, July 2017- ongoing; Kimura, Mari (Violinist); 3 websites in 3 archived websites
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of www.marikimura.com and mugicmotion.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the composer's website includes a biography of the artist, information about her project MUGIC, a list of her works, a discography, and a bibliography of her research and publications on topics such as Subharmonics, violin, and the creation of MUGIC.
  Embedded video files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Mari Kimura (b. 1962) is a violinist and composer of pieces primarily for violin and computer music. Her work focuses on expanding the capabilities of the violin; she is the creator of a violin technique called Subharmonics, through which she produces "pitches that sound up to an octave below the violin's lowest string without re-turning." Kimura also created a prototype motion sensor called MUGIC, which enables one to use movements to control virtually anything in software, specifically used by musicians, dancers, artists, and actors on stages. MUGIC was originally built with the intention of capturing nuanced physical data to control parameters in music software.
- King, John, August 2011- ongoing; King, John, 1953 November 28-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of johnkingmusic.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, examples of his music in the form of embedded audio files, a discography of his published albums, scores, reviews of King and his works, events listings, and a blog.
  Embedded video and SoundCloud audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  John King (b. 1953) is a violist, guitarist, and composer from New York. King has composed music for opera, theater, and concert performance. He is the author of multiple operas including ping, WHAT IS THE WORD, impropera, SapphOpera, herzstück/heartpiece, la belle captive, and Dice Thrown. King has served as Professor of Music at New York University and as curator at The Kitchen.
- Kirchoff, Keith, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://keithkirchoff.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; information about his compositions and projects; a calendar of his events; a discography of his published albums; and examples of his works in the form of embedded video files.
  Keith Kirchoff is a pianist, conductor, composer, teacher, and concert curator. His compositions emphasize experimentation and the merging of technology and classical performance. He is also the co-founder and President of SPLICE Music, a program dedicated to the performance, creation, and development of music for performers and electronics.
- Kirst, Patrick, February 2014-ongoing; 4 websites in 4 archived websites
  Patrick Kirst (b.1973) is film and media composer based in Los Angeles. He has created music for Netflix productions such as The Kissing Booth and Woman of the Dead; as well as Amazon Prime titles like Breaking Surface, and Paramount+ production Wasteland, among other titles. His work also includes contributions to blockbuster productions like The Proposal and Sex and the City: The Movie.
  The website features the composer's film credits; embedded audio samples of a selection of Kirst's work; a biography; and a blog for news and personal updates.
  The site was updated significantly in 2017, but crawls before that point are not viewable in Wayback due to a playback error which may be resolved at a later date.
  Portions of the website were crawled separately to attempt adequate capture.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of patrickkirst.com and wix.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Kirsten, Amy Beth, April 2014- ongoing; Kirsten, Amy Beth, 1972-; 1 websites 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of amybethkirsten.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Amy Beth Kirsten (b. 1972) is a composer and director based in New Haven, Connecticut. Her works merge music with language, technology, and theatre. She was a leader of the HOWL ensemble from 2012 to 2018. Notable works by Kirsten include Savior (2018), which is a retelling of Joan of Arc's story, and QUIXOTE (2017), a theatrical work inspired by Cervantes' novel. Kirsten has been recognized by The American Academy of Arts and Letters, the John S. Guggenheim Foundation, and the Rockefeller Foundation.
  The website features a list of works sorted by category; upcoming events; a discography; a biography; a catalog; teaching and contact information; and a shop. The website also showcases Kirsten's visual art pieces using different media and techniques, including photography, charcoal, video stills, and detritus.
- Kline, Phil, July 2017- ongoing; Kline, Phil, 1953-; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of philkline.com and unsilentnight.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website was rescoped to also include Box domains.
  The composer's website contains a biography of the artist; information about his compositions; examples of his music in the form of embedded audio and video recordings; examples of his prose work which mostly consists of reviews of other musicians and information about his own performances; contact information; and news about the artist. His web presence also includes the website for Unsilent Night, an original composition by Phil Kline, written specifically to be heard outdoors in the month of December.
  Phil Kline (b. 1953) is a composer and performer of music inspired and influenced by New York's downtown scene. Kline's repertoire includes electronic, vocal, solo, chamber, dance, theater, and orchestral music, as well as music for film and installations. He was the founder of the rock band The Del-Byzanteens. Kline also collaborated with Nan Goldin on the soundtrack of Goldin's autobiographical film titled The Ballad of Sexual Dependency.
- Klucevsek, Guy, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5880; 2 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.guyklucevsek.com/ and http://www.ksanti.net/free-reed/essays/misdemeanors.html in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Some external sites were included due to their contextual value to the site that is the focus of this crawl. These sites are http://www.ksanti.net/free-reed/essays/misdemeanors.html.
  Flash based embedded video and audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; his resume; examples of his work in the form of embedded audio and video files; information about his accordions; performances; compositions; and projects; images of Klucevsek; and quotes from the press about the artist.
  Guy Klucevsek is an accordionist and a founding member of Accordion Tribe, an ensemble of international composers and accordion players.
  Accordion Tribe
- Kouyoumdjian, Mary, August 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of marykouyoumdjian.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist; information about her current and past projects; a calendar of her events; a discography; reviews of Kouyoumdjian and her compositions; and contact information.
  Embedded Vimeo video files and SoundCloud audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Mary Kouyoumdjian (b. 1983) is a New York-based Armenian-American composer whose works include concert pieces, film scores, and multimedia collaborations. Kouyoumdjian's work often includes recorded testimonies of people as well as field recordings to speak about matters of social and political importance. She is also a new music advocate and a co-founder of the annual conference New Music Gathering.
- Koykkar, Joseph, April 2014- ongoing; Koykkar, Joseph, 1951-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of josephkoykkar.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Joseph Koykkar (b. 1951) is a composer of classical, avant-garde, rock, and blues music. One of his notable titles include Out Front, which was a 2006 Grammy contestant for the category "Best Contemporary Classical Composition." He is also the founder and artistic director of the Madison New Music Ensemble.
  The website features a biography, scores, audio, a discography, videos, commissioned works, press reviews, photos, and contact information. This description is based on the January 2023 crawl.
- Krimitzá, Vasilikí, September 2017-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of krimitzavasiliki.wordpress.com and krimitzavasiliki.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Scope was expanded in an attempt to capture Google Drive files.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist; examples of her works with audio and video files; a list of concerts; excerpts of reviews of her work in English and German; and contact information.
  Images and Google Drive files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Vasilikí Krimitzá is a Greek composer based in New York City. Krimitzá composes classically-influenced vocal, acousmatic, and instrumental music for large and small ensemble performance. Examples of recent titles composed by Krimitzá include thousand voices, Ήλιο – 3, and Streichquartett No. 1. She holds a PhD in composition from New York University and is a professor at Otterbein University.
- La Barbara, Joan, July 2017- ongoing; La Barbara, Joan, 1947-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of joanlabarbara.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; a list of her compositions; a discography of her published works; a calendar of her performances; a description of her works meant to accompany films; images of the artist; examples of her music in the form of embedded audio files; reviews of her work; La Barbara's resume and CV; examples of her voice-over work; and links to videos of her performances.
  Parts of the live site involving Flash, JavaScript, and SoundCloud were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Joan La Barbara (b. 1947) is a composer and vocal performer. Her work is characterized by its exploration of the range of the human voice as an instrument. In her music, La Barbara experiments with multiple vocal techniques including multiphonics, circular singing, ululation, and glottal clicks. Besides vocal works, her compositional repertoire also includes music for chamber ensembles, music theater, orchestra, and works with interactive technology. Examples of notable titles by La Barbara include in the dream time, Calligraphy II/Shadows, and Dragons on the Wall.
- La Rose, Andrea, February 2014- ongoing; cuid5907; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of reloadsanear.com and two-chords.tumblr.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The artist's website contains a biography of La Rose; an artist statement; information about her work as a composer, flutist, and educator; blogs containing her written works; information about her flute method; photographs; and her blog. Her web presence also includes Two Chords, a tumblr blog created by Andrea La Rose on songs with only two chords. The website contains embedded video examples of her two-chord songs.
  Embedded Bandcamp audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Andrea La Rose (b. 1998) is a flutist, performer, educator, and composer. She has been involved with many ensembles, and her work specializes in chamber music and improvisational compositions.
- Lara, Felipe, February 2015-ongoing; Lara, Felipe, 1979-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of felipelara.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Felipe Lara (b. 1979) is a Brazilian-American composer of orchestral, chamber, vocal, film, electroacoustic, and popular music. Notable works by Lara include his Double Concerto, which was a Pulitzer Prize finalist in 2024. He is an Associate Professor and Chair of the Composition Department at The Peabody Institute of Johns Hopkins University.
  As of March 2025, the website contains news about the artist's career; a list of events; a biography; a list of works with embedded media and program notes; a list of embedded videos which include works by Lara as well as interviews with the artist; press features; a discography; and contact information.
- Lam, Angel, April 2014-ongoing; Lam, Angel, 1978-; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of angellam.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Angel Lam (b. 1978) is a composer; librettist; and artistic director with a background in western classical, folk music, and Chinese music. Her work explores the themes of life and death; relationships; memories; and inspiration. Examples of notable works by Lam include the musical June Lovers; the off-Broadway production of A Dream of Red Pavilions; and the co-creation of Color of the Mind, a short film for which she wrote the story and music.
  It contains a biography of the artist, a list of her works with embedded audio files and accompanying images, news about the artist, an image gallery with photos of Lam in different settings, and her contact information. The website was originally captured from 2014-2015, and then reactivated in 2025. Her web presence also includes the website for her musical, Lost Shanghai.
- Lang, David, August 2011-ongoing; 3 websites in 3 archived websites
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of davidlangmusic.com, redpoppymusic.com, and bangonacan.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; interviews; information about his works and projects;, articles written about Lang and his compositions; a discography of his albums; and a calendar of his events. His web presence also includes the websites for Bang on a Can (his performing arts organization) and Red Poppy Music (his publishing company).
  Embedded SoundCloud audio files and some aspects of the site layout were not captured due to technological constraints.
  David Lang (b. 1957) is a New York-based composer of classically-influenced opera, chamber, orchestra, and solo pieces. He is also a co-founder of the musical collective Bang on a Can. Lang was awarded a Pulitzer Prize for Music in 2008 for the score of the little match girl passion, a work for four voices and percussion. Some of his more recent works include the operas prisoner of the state and note to a friend. Lang is also a Professor of Music Composition at the Yale School of Music.
- Lash, Hannah, July 2010-ongoing; Lash, Hannah, 1981-; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of hannahlash.com and www.lashdance.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The artist's website was previously located at www.hannalash.com. It contained a biography; information about her works; examples of her solo performances on the harp in the form of embedded video files; a calendar of her events; links to news about her and reviews of her works; and links to the websites of other composers and programs with whom she has worked. As of this writing (2025), the website is located at www.lashdance.org. It contains her works for orchestra; chamber orchestra; chamber orchestra with chorus; string ensemble; solo instruments with orchestra or ensemble; chamber music, chorus; and vocal/staged solo. It also contains a biography of the artist, harp program offerings, dance collaborations, music, and videos.
  Hannah Lash (b. 1981) is an American composer, dancer, and performer of music for the harp as well as chamber, vocal, and orchestral groups. Her work focuses on expanding the harp repertoire that is set to modern dance. Examples of pieces authored by Lash include Forestallings, Facets of Motion, Concerto for Harp and Chamber Orchestra, Moth Sketches, From the Depths I Cry Out, and Blood Rose.
  Parts of the live site involving JavaScript and YouTube were not captured due to technological constraints.
- Latham, Clara Hunter, August 2017- ongoing; Latham, Clara; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of claralatham.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contained a biography of the artist; information about her works and projects; articles written about Latham and her compositions; and examples of her music in the form of embedded audio and video files. As of 2025, http://www.claralatham.com/ no longer exists on the live web and moved to https://clara-latham.squarespace.com/. The website contains class syllabi, scores, and in-progress projects.
  Embedded SoundCloud audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Clara Hunter Latham is a composer and musicologist. Her musical pieces are classically-influenced, but interdisciplinary. Hunter uses traditional instruments and voice, combining aspects of popular and experimental genres. Examples of notable works by Latham include the titles Bertha the Mom and Giselle of Loneliness. As an artist and researcher, Latham focuses on the relationships between sound, technology, sexuality, and the body. She also studies the "shifts in listening both to musical tones and to the voice that took place alongside the development of sound recording."
- Lauten, Elodie, March 2015; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of elodielauten.net in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Elodie Lauten (1950-2014) was a French-born American composer and improviser, as well as an accomplished pianist based in New York City. Her compositions included operas, theater pieces, orchestral, chamber, and instrumental music. Lauten was also considered a pioneer of postminimalism. Her notable works include The Death of Don Juan, Deus ex Machina, OrfReo, Sonate Ordinaire, and Waking New York.
  The website was captured once in March 2015. It contained an obituary, music, videos, and news archives. As of 2023, the website is no longer online.
- Leach, Mary Jane, April 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of www.mjleach.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; information about her works and projects; articles written about Leach and her compositions; and examples of her music in the form of embedded audio and video files.
  Mary Jane Leach (b. 1949) is a composer and performer of choral pieces using non-traditional acoustics that she employs to create environments that have been described as "spiritual" and "otherworldly." Her work is focused on how the properties of sound interact with space. Leach was based in New York City and later moved to upstate New York, where she purchased an old church that she turned into her home and performance space, allowing her to interact with the acoustics of its architecture.
- Lee, Andrew McKenna, April 2014- June 2017; cuid5865; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of andrewmckennalee.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website no longer exists in the live web. It contained a biography of the artist; a calendar of his events; news and press relating to the artist and his works; a catalog of his compositions and other projects; and a discography of his published works.
  Andrew McKenna Lee (b. 1974) is a composer and guitarist. Lee's style is influenced by classical, progressive rock, and psychedelic music. He has played guitar in both solo performances and as a part of several ensembles, among which are included the art rock ensemble The Knells, which combines Renaissance-inspired vocal polyphony with influences of different types of rock music. His debut record release titled Gravity and Air was picked by TimeOut Chicago as one of the top ten classical recordings of 2009. Other titles by Lee include Solar/Electric and Electric Counterpoint. He also works as a recording engineer and producer.
- Lee, Yoon-Ji, February 2015-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of yoonjilee.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Yoon-Ji Lee is a South Korean composer of electroacoustic music based in New York and Boston. Her works combine interdisciplinary, multimedia, and intercultural elements. Her work often touches on themes such as contemporary society, history, and culture. She is also an associate professor at the Berklee College of Music.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography; embedded video and audio files; a discography; compositions; a list of past and upcoming performances; press reviews; information about her research; photos of the artist; and contact information.